Finding Aid for Andrew Dickson White lectures, 1861-1912
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Andrew Dickson White lectures 1861-1912
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.
0.5 linear feet (24 items)
[7213] DA 2; W582; L471
Professor of history at University of Michigan, later President of Cornell University, Minister to Russia, and Ambassador to Germany. Printed copies of lectures and writings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was assembled from various sources, some items originally came from the library of Corydon L. Ford.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Professor of history at University of Michigan 1856-1865, later President of Cornell University, Minister to Russia, and Ambassador to Germany.
The Andrew Dickson White collections consists of 24 printed copies of lectures and writings on variety of topics in history and political science, and addresses delivered on ceremonial occasions.
Subjects:
Cornell University.; Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1874.; Russell, William Howard, Sir, 1820-1907.; Western Reserve University.
Genre Terms:
Lectures.
- Lectures
  - Address at the funeral of Edward Lasker, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Address on agricultural education ..., 1869
  - The diplomatic service of the United States, with some hints toward its reform, 1905
  - Education in political science, 1879
  - Evolution and revolution, 1890
  - Fiat money inflation in France ..., 1933
  - A letter of Andrew Dickson White, LL.D., resigning the presidency of Cornell University ..., 1885
  - A letter to Wm. Howard Russell, LL.D. on passages in his "Diary North and South." [London Edition], 1863
  - A letter to Wm. Howard Russell, LL.D. on passages in his "Diary North and South." [University of Michigan edition], 1863
  - The message of the nineteenth century to the twentieth, 1883
  - My reminiscences of Ezra Cornell ..., 1890
  - The new Germany, 1882
  - Outlines of a course of lectures on history, addressed to the senior class, (second semester, 1860), in the State University of Michigan
  - Outlines of a course of lectures on history ... (second semester, 1861)
  - A patriotic investment: Being an address ... at the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Yale Class of 1853 ..., 1903
  - The presidency of Cornell University, 1885
  - The question between the United States and Russia, 1912
  - The relations of the national and state governments to advanced education, 1874
  - Review of the Governor's message: Speech of Hon. Andrew D. White of Onondaga in Senate, March, 1864
  - Some important questions in higher education, 1885
  - Some practical influences of German thought upon the United States, 1884
  - Two addresses at Cleveland, Ohio, 25 and 26 October, 1882
    - I. On the plan of Western Reserve University
    - II. On the education of the freedmen
  - The warfare of science, 1880